(futuristic sound)
- Awesome, we have our
scene setup here and you
can see the cool sky box all around it to
create this cool nighttime
effect at the bottom.
So we're gonna do a little
bit more scene setup.
So, in this game, what
we're actually gonna do is
we're gonna use one of
our primitive shapes.
So in our hierarchy, we
can go to the top
or right click in the hierarchy,
so we're gonna make a 3D
object and we're going to
make a sphere.
Now, you can see our sphere is floating off
onto the side so that's
definitely not good.
So what we're gonna do first is we're just
going to reset this back
to the center of our world.
So I'm just going to
use the icon on the
right side of transform.
Click on it and then reset position.
And there you go, now our
sphere is exactly in the center.
I'm just going to rename this because this
will actually be what our player controls
so this will be the player.
Now, if you can see our little sphere,
if we focus on it with
F, it's kind of small.
Especially in the game view.
So what we're going to do is
we're just gonna scale it up.
So we'll actually just
set all of these values
on the X,Y, and Z to 1.5 manually.
That looks pretty good.
Let's see, we have a
little bit of clipping
through the ground so
we're actually just going
to move the sphere up a little bit
so that way it's at
least above the ground.
So now that we have our
sphere in the world here,
we're going to use a rigid body
so we can actually use
physics and then gravity
will actually make this
sphere fall onto this plane.
So we're going to go to the
inspector on the right side
click add component, type in rigid,
so we have our rigid
body and we apply that
and it already uses
gravity which is great.
And then one little bit of
setup that we're gonna do is
we're actually going to apply
textures onto this object now.
So, if we go to our project
window and then we go
to our textures folder
underneath our course library,
if we expand that you can
see all of these different
textures that we have,
so similarly to how we
could apply textures to
some of our background
scenes we can actually apply
textures onto our characters.
So, I'm going to, in this
case, let's see let's try
this checkered texture.
So I can just drag it
directly onto the player
and it will immediately
change the texture.
Or, I can take on of the
other textures and I can
drag it directly onto
our object in the scene
and it'll change it that way.
So texture mapping is
a really useful way to
be able to apply different textures
and materials onto our objects.
If we wanted to make our ball shinier
or use a different color
or something like that
we can use texture maps
to be able to do so.
So, what you're gonna do is you're gonna
go into your hierarchy, right click,
create a 3D object, and
we're going to make a sphere.
And then your sphere you're
going to rename to player.
You're going to reset the position so that
it's back at 000.
Scale up your sphere to
be 1.5 on the X,Y, and Z.
And then you're probably
going to want to reposition
your sphere on the Y axis.
Then you're going to add a rigid body.
And then last but not least you're gonna
go into your assets in the course library
in your textures folder
and you're going to
click and drag a texture
either onto the player
in the hierarchy or in the scene view.
Now it's your turn.
(futuristic sound)